<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
    <title>Crypto News 🇨🇭</title>
    <link href="https://cryptoswiss.news/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://cryptoswiss.news" />
    <updated>2024-11-22T13:45:55+01:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Crypto Swiss News Team</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://cryptoswiss.news</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Switzerland Adopts a ‘Tech Neutral’ Approach to AI Regulation</title>
        <author>
            <name>Crypto Swiss News Team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://cryptoswiss.news/switzerland-adopts-a-tech-neutral-approach-to-ai-regulation.html"/>
        <id>https://cryptoswiss.news/switzerland-adopts-a-tech-neutral-approach-to-ai-regulation.html</id>

        <updated>2024-11-22T13:45:55+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    As nations around the world scramble to regulate artificial intelligence (AI), Switzerland is taking a distinct approach: a “tech-neutral” stance that prioritizes sector-based use cases over blanket regulations. While remaining outside the European Union (EU), Switzerland continues to shape its AI policies with a focus&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>As nations around the world scramble to regulate artificial intelligence (AI), Switzerland is taking a distinct approach: a <strong>“tech-neutral” stance</strong> that prioritizes sector-based use cases over blanket regulations. While remaining outside the European Union (EU), Switzerland continues to shape its AI policies with a focus on fostering innovation and influencing global discussions on AI governance.</p>
<h3><strong>Switzerland’s Unique Position in AI Policy</strong></h3>
<p>Switzerland, renowned for its technological prowess, is no stranger to cutting-edge advancements. It hosts <strong>Crypto Valley</strong>, a global hub for blockchain innovation, and <strong>ETH Zurich</strong>, one of the world’s leading AI research institutions. However, unlike its EU neighbors, Switzerland is not bound by the recently implemented EU AI Act, giving it the flexibility to carve out its own regulatory path.</p>
<p>Cointelegraph spoke to experts like <strong>Ayisha Piotti</strong>, head of Switzerland’s Annual AI Policy Summit, and <strong>Alexander Brunner</strong>, an adviser to AI and blockchain companies, to unpack the country’s approach to AI regulation.</p>
<h3><strong>The Role of Democracy and Research in Shaping AI Policy</strong></h3>
<p>Switzerland’s <strong>stable democracy</strong> and emphasis on transparent dialogue form the foundation of its regulatory approach. Piotti highlighted the importance of public understanding and participation in shaping laws:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We cannot just make laws; we have to make sure that the people are with us and they understand. That’s ingrained in our DNA.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Brunner noted that Switzerland’s long-standing reputation for research excellence—bolstered by ETH Zurich—has positioned the country as a leader in both AI and blockchain. For 13 consecutive years, Switzerland has topped the <strong>UN Intellectual Property Organization’s innovation rankings</strong>. This focus on research ensures that AI development is supported by robust academic and technological foundations.</p>
<h3><strong>A Tech-Neutral Regulatory Approach</strong></h3>
<p>Switzerland’s neutrality extends beyond politics, influencing its stance on AI regulation. The Swiss approach emphasizes <strong>use-case-specific regulations</strong> rather than broad, technology-specific rules.</p>
<p>Piotti explained:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We didn’t want to implement regulation on a technology specifically. We wanted to look at the technology in a certain use case and then fill in the gap regarding legislation.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This sector-specific framework allows Switzerland to update existing laws rather than create entirely new ones for AI. Brunner described this as a careful balancing act:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Carefully balancing sensible regulation with strong research is the foundation of Switzerland’s success. Innovation needs freedom to be creative.”</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><strong>Collaboration and Global Influence</strong></h3>
<p>Despite its non-EU status, Switzerland plays a significant role in shaping international AI policies. Piotti noted that while Swiss businesses must comply with the EU AI Act to operate within the EU, the regulatory impact of the EU often extends globally through the "Brussels effect."</p>
<p>Switzerland’s role as a <strong>trusted moderator</strong> in global forums further enhances its influence. Geneva hosts several international organizations, where Switzerland actively participates in shaping AI governance. For example, Switzerland leads the AI working group within the <strong>Council of Europe</strong>, which includes participation from 46 member states, the United States, and Japan.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Even though we are a small country, we want to have a big share of voice when it comes to international forums,” Piotti emphasized.</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><strong>Balancing Innovation and Regulation</strong></h3>
<p>Switzerland’s approach ensures that AI innovation is not stifled by overregulation. By adopting a pragmatic, tech-neutral framework, the country reinforces its position as a hub for AI development while fostering collaboration on a global scale.</p>
<p>Brunner concluded:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We have an outsized voice despite our lack of size. This is highly important in a polarized global political environment.”</p>
</blockquote>
<h3><strong>Looking Ahead</strong></h3>
<p>As Switzerland continues to balance innovation with sensible regulation, its tech-neutral approach provides a model for other nations navigating the complexities of AI governance. Through collaboration, inclusivity, and its commitment to research, Switzerland is not only advancing its AI capabilities but also playing a pivotal role in shaping the future of global AI policy.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Web3 and Crypto2030 Converge in Davos: Insights into the Future of Blockchain</title>
        <author>
            <name>Crypto Swiss News Team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit-4.html"/>
        <id>https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit-4.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/4/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-11-21T15:30:39+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/4/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" alt="" />
                    The blockchain, crypto, and finance industries came together in January 2024 for the inaugural CRYPTO2030 event in Davos, Switzerland. Against the scenic backdrop of the Alps, this Web3-focused gathering brought industry leaders, experts, and visionaries to discuss the future of decentralized technology and its transformative&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/4/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>The blockchain, crypto, and finance industries came together in January 2024 for the inaugural <strong>CRYPTO2030</strong> event in Davos, Switzerland. Against the scenic backdrop of the Alps, this Web3-focused gathering brought industry leaders, experts, and visionaries to discuss the future of decentralized technology and its transformative potential.</p>
<h3><strong>A Community-Driven Web3 Movement</strong></h3>
<p>Web3 thrives on collaboration and shared innovation, making gatherings like CRYPTO2030 essential for shaping the industry. Positioned as a key event in Europe, CRYPTO2030 leveraged interactive formats, including thematic dialogues, roundtables, and networking sessions, to foster knowledge exchange and strategic partnerships.</p>
<p>Notable speakers from organizations such as <strong>DWF Labs</strong>, <strong>Binance Institutional</strong>, and <strong>Yield Guild Games</strong> addressed critical issues, including central bank digital currencies (CBDCs), asset tokenization, and digital identity. By facilitating meaningful discussions and highlighting innovative projects, the event underscored the collective mission to propel blockchain and Web3 into mainstream relevance.</p>
<h3><strong>Key Themes from CRYPTO2030</strong></h3>
<h4><strong>Decentralized Governance and Sustainability</strong></h4>
<p>A standout topic at CRYPTO2030 was decentralized governance, with experts exploring how such models could redefine decision-making processes across the digital economy. Sustainability also took center stage, with discussions on green blockchain technologies and the role of crypto in environmental conservation. These themes reflect the industry’s growing focus on aligning technological advancement with ecological responsibility.</p>
<h4><strong>Digital Identity and Privacy</strong></h4>
<p>Another highlight was the exploration of digital identity solutions. Industry leaders shared insights on improving user privacy, leveraging asset tokenization, and enabling cross-chain integration for seamless digital asset management. These innovations aim to enhance liquidity in conventional markets and drive more secure and efficient user experiences.</p>
<h4><strong>The Role of Web3 in Global Finance</strong></h4>
<p>Participants discussed the profound impact of Web3 on global finance, touching on topics such as stablecoins, CBDCs, and the integration of cryptocurrencies into international trade and remittances. These dialogues painted a picture of how decentralized technologies could reshape global financial systems and create new opportunities for economic inclusion.</p>
<h3><strong>The Vision for 2030 and Beyond</strong></h3>
<p>CRYPTO2030’s core mission is to chart a comprehensive roadmap for the future of Web3. From cultural shifts driven by NFTs to the financial transformation enabled by decentralized technologies, the event laid the groundwork for a more sustainable, inclusive, and empowered digital landscape.</p>
<p>A key takeaway from the event was the power of community in driving innovation. “Transformation happens because of one vision but is sustained by a united collective and community determined to move in the same direction,” the CRYPTO2030 team emphasized. They highlighted that the future of crypto is shaped not by a few individuals but by the collective contributions of builders, developers, founders, and investors.</p>
<h3><strong>Looking Ahead</strong></h3>
<p>CRYPTO2030 underscored the importance of gatherings like these in steering the crypto and blockchain industries toward maturity and mainstream adoption. By championing decentralization, sustainability, and user empowerment, the event positioned itself as a catalyst for innovation and collaboration, setting the stage for groundbreaking developments in the Web3 space.</p>
<p>As the industry evolves, CRYPTO2030’s vision of a decentralized, sustainable, and inclusive digital future offers a clear pathway to harnessing the transformative potential of blockchain and Web3 technologies.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Switzerland’s Financial Regulator Tightens Rules for Crypto Transactions</title>
        <author>
            <name>Crypto Swiss News Team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit-3.html"/>
        <id>https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit-3.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/3/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-11-21T15:30:33+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/3/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" alt="" />
                    The Swiss Financial Market Supervisory Authority (FINMA) has announced an extension of its Anti-Money Laundering (AML) ordinance, reinforcing identity verification requirements for certain cryptocurrency transactions. In a notice published on Nov. 2, FINMA confirmed its commitment to enforcing a transaction threshold of 1,000 Swiss francs&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/3/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>The Swiss Financial Market Supervisory Authority (FINMA) has announced an extension of its Anti-Money Laundering (AML) ordinance, reinforcing identity verification requirements for certain cryptocurrency transactions.</p>
<p>In a notice published on Nov. 2, FINMA confirmed its commitment to enforcing a transaction threshold of 1,000 Swiss francs (approximately $997). The rule applies to transactions involving virtual currencies exchanged for cash or other anonymous payment methods. The updated regulation aligns with Switzerland’s broader Anti-Money Laundering Act and its government’s AML Ordinance.</p>
<h3><strong>Strengthening AML Measures</strong></h3>
<p>FINMA reported receiving significant feedback on the decision to lower the reporting threshold for virtual currency transactions. The regulator defended its stance, citing increased risks and instances of abuse in the crypto sector. To mitigate these risks, FINMA requires technical safeguards to prevent exceeding the 1,000 CHF threshold for linked transactions within a 30-day period.</p>
<p>This isn’t the first adjustment FINMA has made to transaction reporting limits. In January 2020, the regulator reduced the threshold from 5,000 CHF (around $4,944) to 1,000 CHF ($988), citing concerns over rising money laundering activities in the crypto space.</p>
<h3><strong>Regulation Timeline and Implementation</strong></h3>
<p>The extended ordinance is set to take effect in January 2023. By reinforcing these measures, FINMA aims to enhance transparency and accountability within the rapidly evolving cryptocurrency market.</p>
<h3><strong>Lugano’s Crypto Progress</strong></h3>
<p>Switzerland continues to make waves in crypto adoption. Recently, Lugano hosted the <strong>Plan B conference</strong> on Oct. 28, solidifying its position as a hub for blockchain innovation. During the event, the local government announced an economic partnership with El Salvador, which includes plans for the Central American nation to establish a physical presence in Lugano—dubbed by some as a "Bitcoin embassy."</p>
<p>Lugano has become a focal point for crypto enthusiasts demonstrating the real-world utility of Bitcoin, the Lightning Network, and other digital assets. The city’s proactive embrace of cryptocurrency aligns with Switzerland’s broader vision for integrating blockchain technology into its economy while maintaining robust regulatory oversight.</p>
<p>For the latest updates on crypto regulations and innovations in Switzerland, follow Swiss Crypto News.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>McDonald’s Embraces Bitcoin and Tether in Lugano, Switzerland</title>
        <author>
            <name>Crypto Swiss News Team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit-2.html"/>
        <id>https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit-2.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/2/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-11-21T15:30:26+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/2/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" alt="" />
                    Global fast-food giant McDonald’s takes a bold step into the crypto space, accepting Bitcoin and Tether as payment in the Swiss city of Lugano. McDonald’s, a globally recognized name in fast food, has started accepting Bitcoin (BTC) and Tether (USDT) for payments in Lugano, Switzerland.
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/2/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p><em>Global fast-food giant McDonald’s takes a bold step into the crypto space, accepting Bitcoin and Tether as payment in the Swiss city of Lugano.</em></p>
<p>McDonald’s, a globally recognized name in fast food, has started accepting Bitcoin (BTC) and Tether (USDT) for payments in Lugano, Switzerland. This initiative positions the 63,000-resident city, nestled in the Italian-speaking region of the country, as a burgeoning hub for cryptocurrency adoption in Western Europe.</p>
<p>A video shared by Bitcoin Magazine on Oct. 3 showcased the seamless process of ordering food via McDonald’s digital kiosk and completing the payment using a mobile app. Both the Bitcoin and Tether logos were prominently displayed on the payment terminal, reflecting Lugano's growing crypto-friendly environment.</p>
<p>This move aligns with Lugano’s “Plan B” initiative, announced in March 2022, when the city entered a memorandum of understanding with Tether Operations Limited. The partnership has ambitious goals: making Bitcoin, Tether, and Lugano’s own LVGA token legal tender within the city.</p>
<h3><strong>Crypto-Friendly Innovations in Lugano</strong></h3>
<p>Under Plan B, Tether has allocated significant resources to bolster crypto adoption in the city. Key components include:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>A $106 million fund:</strong> Designed to support crypto startups in the region.</li>
<li><strong>A $3 million fund:</strong> Aimed at incentivizing local shops and businesses to accept cryptocurrency payments.</li>
</ul>
<p>Residents of Lugano can now pay taxes, parking fees, tuition, and public services using cryptocurrencies. Over 200 businesses in the city are expected to integrate crypto payments, further embedding digital currencies into daily life.</p>
<h3><strong>McDonald’s Crypto Journey</strong></h3>
<p>McDonald’s has shown openness to cryptocurrency in other parts of the world as well. In September 2021, El Salvador made Bitcoin legal tender, and McDonald’s began accepting it across all 19 of its outlets in the country. Lugano now joins this trend, making it one of the first cities in Europe to see McDonald’s adopt cryptocurrency payments.</p>
<h3><strong>Driving Education and Adoption</strong></h3>
<p>Plan B isn’t just about payment solutions. It’s also about education. Paolo Ardoino, CTO of Tether and Bitfinex, shared in June that Lugano is hosting a two-week blockchain and cryptocurrency educational program. This initiative aims to demystify blockchain technology and further encourage its adoption in the region.</p>
<h3><strong>Lugano: A Crypto Innovation Hotspot</strong></h3>
<p>With Lugano leading the way in cryptocurrency adoption and McDonald’s participation reinforcing mainstream acceptance, the city is setting an example for integrating digital currencies into everyday commerce. As the initiative unfolds, Lugano is well on its way to becoming a cornerstone of crypto innovation in Europe.</p>
<p>For more updates on crypto adoption in Switzerland, stay tuned to Swiss Crypto News.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>One in Nine Swiss Residents Invest in Cryptocurrencies: Curiosity Over Profit</title>
        <author>
            <name>Crypto Swiss News Team</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit.html"/>
        <id>https://cryptoswiss.news/one-in-nine-swiss-residents-invest-in-cryptocurrencies-curiosity-over-profit.html</id>
        <media:content url="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/1/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" medium="image" />

        <updated>2024-11-21T15:28:05+01:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/1/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" alt="" />
                    A growing number of Swiss residents are dipping their toes into the world of cryptocurrencies, with one in nine now holding digital assets like Bitcoin and Ether. However, curiosity—not financial gain—is the main driver behind this trend, according to a recent study by the Lucerne&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <p><img src="https://cryptoswiss.news/media/posts/1/shutterstock_1708749826_small.jpg.webp" class="type:primaryImage" alt="" /></p>
                <p>A growing number of Swiss residents are dipping their toes into the world of cryptocurrencies, with one in nine now holding digital assets like Bitcoin and Ether. However, curiosity—not financial gain—is the main driver behind this trend, according to a recent study by the Lucerne University of Applied Sciences and Arts conducted on behalf of Postfinance.</p>
<h3><strong>Low but Emerging Interest in Crypto Assets</strong></h3>
<p>Despite the notable figure of crypto adopters, interest in cryptocurrencies remains moderate across the Swiss population. The study revealed that only 8% of respondents are “rather strongly” or “very strongly” interested in digital assets. Meanwhile, the vast majority—approximately 80%—have never invested in cryptocurrencies.</p>
<p>Bitcoin leads the pack in recognition, with 87% of respondents familiar with the cryptocurrency, followed by Ether at 35%. The findings suggest that while awareness is widespread, active engagement remains niche.</p>
<h3><strong>Demographics of Crypto Investors</strong></h3>
<p>The study highlights disparities in crypto investment habits among different demographics:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Gender:</strong> Men are almost three times more likely to invest than women, with 17% of male respondents holding cryptocurrencies compared to just 6% of females.</li>
<li><strong>Income:</strong> Interest rises with income levels—22% of those earning over CHF150,000 annually have invested in crypto assets, compared to only 6% in the income bracket below CHF25,000.</li>
<li><strong>Generations:</strong> Younger individuals are significantly more engaged. Among Gen Z (aged 18–27) and Gen Y (aged 28–41), 13% and 18% respectively have made investments, in stark contrast to the 4% of Baby Boomers (aged 58–74).</li>
</ul>
<h3><strong>Smaller Investments Driven by Curiosity</strong></h3>
<p>For most Swiss crypto investors, the financial stakes remain modest. About 31% of respondents hold less than CHF1,000 in cryptocurrencies. This trend reflects the experimental nature of many investments. The primary motivation cited by 71% of investors is curiosity or personal interest, while 50% are driven by the potential for returns.</p>
<p>“Returns and diversification of portfolios play a role,” the study notes, “but for many, they remain secondary motivations.”</p>
<h3><strong>Popular Platforms and Providers</strong></h3>
<p>The study also sheds light on where Swiss investors prefer to trade cryptocurrencies. The most popular platforms include Revolut, Swissquote, and Binance, which cater to both novice and experienced investors. The accessibility and user-friendly nature of these platforms likely contribute to their popularity.</p>
<h3><strong>A Nascent Market with Room to Grow</strong></h3>
<p>The findings paint a picture of a cautious yet curious population engaging with the world of cryptocurrencies. While interest remains concentrated among younger, wealthier men, the increasing accessibility of platforms and ongoing growth in crypto awareness suggest potential for broader adoption.</p>
<p>As the Swiss financial sector increasingly embraces cryptocurrencies—with over a quarter of banks now offering crypto-related services—the nation seems poised to continue exploring this evolving digital frontier.</p>
<p>For more insights and the latest updates on cryptocurrencies in Switzerland, stay tuned to <em>Media Crypto Swiss News</em>.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
